SAI SURESH BATRAJU





saisure18@gmail.com 🕓 8555897152 👔 linkedin.com/in/sai-suresh-batraju-846b75204

PROFILE

Talented and accomplished Test Engineer with 4 years of experience seeking a technically challenging position in the area of Software Testing, which allows me to pursuit career advancement by expanding my knowledge and skills and to propel an organisation's success.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

02/2022 - 07/2023

QA Engineer (Pepper Content Global Private Limited)

- Skilled in understanding Software Requirement Specification and identifying all possible Scenarios
- Following QA processes + getting product sign-off and review
- Monitoring the errors on Elastic Kibana and reporting to dev team
- Coordinated closely with Production Department to recognise the nature of incoming defect calls and recommended system revisions to avoid recurrence of quality issues.
- · Raising, tracking & closing defects in Linear & Clickup
- Involved in cross browsing testing of the application on various browsers to ensure it functions
- Extensive knowledge in Writing Test Cases
- · Experienced in Regression Testing, Functional, Integration and System Testing
- · Experience working in an Agile environment/team focusing on sprint-by-sprint deliveries
- Ability work closely with Developers and Product Owners to ensure features/bug fixes are 'shippable'
- Contribute to sprint planning, sprint review/retrospectives and daily stand-ups meetings
- Experience in preparing Weekly status reports and Daily status reports
- Ability to work under deadlines, worked as an active team member and willingness to accept responsibilities
- · Actively involved in various phases of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) including QA life cycle.
- Planned, developed, scheduled and executed the quality assurance testing activities
- · Reviewed use case, wireframes, design mocks and business requirements document with the business development teams to understand the architecture and functionality of the application

04/2021 - 12/2021

Software Engineer (Cognitive Clouds Software Pvt Ltd) Client (Phonepe)

- · Completed functional, end-to-end, regression, and verification tests on various software applications and platforms.
- Coordinated closely with Production Department to recognize the nature of incoming defect calls and recommended system revisions to avoid recurrence of quality issues..
- Strong background with Manual testing, ,Black box testing, Mobile testing.
- · Creation of test designs, test processes, test cases and test data.
- · Updating the App once in a week with latest features
- Testing mobile App to ensure their configuration, operation, and capabilities work efficiently.
- · Testing On both iOS and Android Devices with all versions of the system

05/2019 - 03/2021

Associate Test Engineer(Proxce technologies Pvt Ltd)

- · Completed functional, end-to-end, regression, and verification tests on various software applications and platforms.
- · Collaborated with software development team members to establish immediate resolution of identified issues and provide internal support.
- · Coordinated closely with Production Department to recognise the nature of incoming defect calls and recommended system revisions to avoid recurrence of quality issues.
- Prepared detailed reports on bugs and errors discovered after conducting post-release/postimplementation testing.
- · Executed manual test cases and analysed results which were forwarded to QA Engineers and QA
- Involved in cross browsing testing of the application on various browsers to ensure it functions
- Strong background with Manual testing, Web application testing, Black box testing, Mobile testing.



EDUCATION

2014 - 2018

Btech(EEE), Pragati Engineering College



English

Telugu

Hindi



Functional Testing

System testing

Mobile Testing

Testing iOS&Android apps,Compatibility Testing, ADB Commands,Upgrade Testing,Charles Proxy

Database testing

MySql

Web Testing

Cross browser & Responsive

API Testing

Postman & Swagger

Learning(Core Java with Selenium& RestAssured)

PROJECTS

Pepper Content, QA Engineer

Description:-

Pepper Content enables CMOs at enterprises and fast-growing companies to grow ROI by helping them create high-quality content and track its lifecycle in one collaborative platform.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Analyse the project requirements
- Performed Manual Testing according to software requirement
- Prepare the quality checklist based on the project specification
- Trouble shooting all type of user problems during & After implementation
- Interact with the development team to test the bugs once they were fixed.
- Communicate risk to producers, QA Leads and QA Manager as needed.
- Taking responsibility and working Independently on small to big projects
- Proactive in coordinating with teammates
- Expertise in Bug Reporting & Tracking Process, Bug tracking tools like Linear and Click Up.
- · Participating in all aspects of product testing, including test plan development, execution and delivery of
- well tested solutions with short time to release.
- Partner with Development Manager in collaborating between engineers and QA

PhonePe (Insurance)(Mobile), QA (Test Engineer)

Description:

Wins the best mobile payment product/service category and the technology category at IAMAI India digital awards.Launches Liquid funds, Super funds and 7 more curated MF category products. The PhonePe ATM goes live across 10 lakh stores in 300 cities. Launches Travel Insurance, Coronavirus Insurance, Motor Insurance & more Insurance offerings. Crosses the 250 million registered users mark; market-leading share of over 40% in UPI transactions

Roles and Responsibilities:

- To read all the documents and understand what needs to be tested.
- Develop test cases and prioritise testing activities.
- Execute all the test case and report defects, define severity and priority for each defect.
- Coordinate with the project manager
- Carry out regression testing every time when changes are made to the code to fix defects.
- · Raising, tracking & closing defects in Jira
- Collecting logs and Checking whether payments are done
- Updating the App with latest features and sign off to the builds
- Collaborate closely with other team members and departments.
- Execute all levels of testing (System, Smoke, Sanity, and Regression)
- Testing the Api's on postman provided by Dev team

Airmeet, Test Engineer

Description:

Airmeet is a platform for virtual summits, meetups & workshops with a social lounge to deliver a rich networking experience

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Analyzing user's stories and/use cases/requirements for validity and feasibility.
- Collaborate closely with other team members and departments.
- Execute all levels of testing (System, Smoke, Sanity, and Regression)
- Detect and track software defects and inconsistencies.
- Apply quality engineering principles throughout the Agile product lifecycle.
- · Participating in all aspects of product testing, including test plan development, execution and delivery of
- well tested solutions with short time to release.
- Partner with Development Manager in collaborating between engineers and QA
- Develop test cases and prioritize testing activities.
- Execute all the test case and report defects, define severity and priority for each defect

